Guide to the Washington Square Contemporary Music Society, 1973-2013 MSS.390
Fales Library and Special Collections
The Washington Square Contemporary Music Society Archive
1973-2013
Fales Library and Special Collections
Washington Square Contemporary Music Society
MSS.390
6 boxes
The Washington Square Contemporary Music Society (WSCMS) seeks to further the cause of new music by presenting recent works. The Society was founded in 1976 by composer Brian Fennelly. Louis Karchin, Professor in the Music Department of New York University's Faculty of Arts and Science, joined the directorship in 1980. Both composers had already demonstrated their leadership in contemporary music; prior to joining WSCMS, Mr. Karchin co-founded the Harvard Group for New Music and the Chamber Players of the League/ISCM. Since 1976, established composers whose works have been presented include Shulamit Ran, Morton Feldman, John Adams, Milton Babbitt, John Cage, Elliott Carter, Frank Zappa, Phillip Glass, Joan Tower, John Zorn, George Walker, and Charles Wuorinen, among hundreds more. The collection comprises adminstrative records created by the Society, such as programs, flyers, and grant applications, as well as audio recordings of performances.
Arrangement
This collection is separated into three series:
Series I: Programs and Fliers
Series II: Financial and Grants
Series III: Audio
Series I and II are arranged alphabetically. Series III is arranged by audio format, and chronologically within each format.
Scope and Contents
The Washington Square Contemporary Music Society Archive contains papers and audio recordings produced by the WSCMS. It includes flyers, press clippings, programs and notes from performances, financial material, and audio recordings of many of the concerts held by the Society between 1976 and 2012.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Historical Note
The Washington Square Contemporary Music Society (WSCMS) seeks to further the cause of new music by presenting recent works in exemplary performances. Since 1976, the Society has worked to attract, educate and invigorate audiences for American contemporary music. From its inception, WSCMS has offered nearly 500 performances of carefully selected and rehearsed compositions by both established and upcoming composers; of these, roughly 200 have been World or New York premieres. Established composers whose works have been presented include Shulamit Ran, Morton Feldman, John Adams, Milton Babbitt, John Cage, Elliott Carter, Frank Zappa, Phillip Glass, Joan Tower, John Zorn, George Walker, and Charles Wuorinen, among hundreds more.
The Society was founded in 1976 by composer Brian Fennelly. Louis Karchin, Professor in the Music Department of New York University's Faculty of Arts and Science, joined the directorship in 1980. Both composers had already demonstrated their leadership in contemporary music; prior to joining WSCMS, Mr. Karchin co-founded the Harvard Group for New Music and the Chamber Players of the League/ISCM.
Source: Washington Square Contemporary Music Society website (http://wscmsny.fhkern.com/)
Provenance
The Washington Square Contemporary Music Society Archive was donated to NYU's Fales Library & Special Collections by the Society in 2014.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
Clippings (information artifacts); Fliers (printed matter); Contemporary music.; Audiocassettes.; Programs (documents); Grant proposals.; Washington Square Contemporary Music Society
- Series I: Programs and Flyers
  Scope and Content
  This series contains the fliers announcing concerts for each season of the Washington Square Contemporary Music Society and programs for most of the concerts, with progams notes. It also contains press clippings and review of concerts.
  - Competition for New Music, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Flyers - Season 9-12, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Flyers - Season 13-15, 1989-1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Flyers - Season 16-18, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Flyers - Season 19-21, 1995-1998 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Flyers - Season 22-24, 1998-2001 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Flyers - Season 25-28, 2001-2005 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Flyers - Season 29-32, 2005-2009 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - League of Composers - By-Laws, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Press Clippings, 1982-1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Press Clippings, 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Press Clippings, 2000-2007 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Programs and Notes, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Programs and Notes, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Programs and Notes, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Programs and Notes, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Programs and Notes, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Programs and Notes, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Programs and Notes, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Programs and Notes, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Programs and Notes, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Programs and Notes, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Programs and Notes, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Programs and Notes, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Programs and Notes, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Programs and Notes, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Programs and Notes, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Programs and Notes, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Programs and Notes, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Programs and Notes, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Programs and Notes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Programs and Notes, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Programs and Notes, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Programs and Notes, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Programs and Notes, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Programs and Notes, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Programs and Notes, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Programs and Notes, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Programs and Notes, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Programs and Notes, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Programs and Notes, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Programs and Notes, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Programs and Notes, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Programs and Notes, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Programs and Notes, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Programs and Notes, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Programs and Notes, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Programs and Notes, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Programs and Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Season 24 Packet, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Season 25 Packet, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Season 26 Packet, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Season 27 Packet, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Season 28 Packet, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Season 29 Packet, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Season 30 Packet, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Season 31 Packet, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Season 32 Packet, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Season 33 Packet, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Series II: Financial and Grants
  This series contains all financial material from the Washington Square Contemporary Music Society. It includes grant applications and follow-up papers, budgets, and general financial material.
  - Budget and Grant letters, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Budget and Grant letters, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Budget and Grant letters, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Budget and Grant letters, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Budget and Grant letters, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Budget and Grant letters, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Budget and Grant letters, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Budget and Grant letters, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Budget and Grant letters, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Financial - general, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Financial - general, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Financial - general, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Financial - general, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Financial - general, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Financial - general, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Financial - general, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Financial - general, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Financial - general, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Financial - general, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Financial - general, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Financial - general, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Financial - general, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Financial - general, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Financial - general, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Financial - general, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Financial - general, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Financial - general, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Financial - general, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Financial Statement - year end, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Grants - Alice M. Ditson Fund, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - IRS - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - IRS - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - NEA Application, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - NEA Application, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - NEA Application, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - NEA Application, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - NEA Application, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - NEA Application, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - NEA Application, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - NEA Application, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - NEA Application, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - NEA Application, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - NEA Application, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - NEA Application, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - NEA Application, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - NEA Final reports, 1981-1994 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - NYSCA - Commission, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Report for Fiscal Year 1989 - 1990 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Series III: Audio
  Conditions Governing Access
  Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  Arrangement
  Media is arranged by format, and chronologically within each format. The formats are 1/4" Reel to Reel audio, 1/4" Audiocassette, DAT, and CD.
  - Subseries A: Audio Elements
    - Gabrieli - Canzon Seconda (trans. Yellin); Miller - The Folly Stone (1 of 2), March 12, 1973; ID: 390.0001 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0001)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Format: 1/4" Reel to Reel
    - Gabrieli - Canzon Seconda (trans. Yellin); Fennelly - Prelude and Elegy; Eisler - Klavierstuche, Op. 3; Miller - The Folly Stone (1 of 2), March 12, 1973; ID: 390.0002 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0002)
    - Wolpe - Two-part Inventions (1948), Form (1959), Suite for Piano (1939); Fennelly - Prelude and Elegy (1973), March 12, 1973; ID: 390.0003 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0003)
    - Stravinsky - Two Poems of Balmont, Three Japanese Lyrics; Sir - Composition for Piano (1966), April 5, 1973; ID: 390.0004 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0004)
    - Yellin - The Queen's Aria, from Abylar; Stravinsky - Two Poems of Balmont, Three Japanese Lyrics; Ravel - Trois Peimes de Mallarme, April 5, 1973; ID: 390.0005 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0005)
    - Fennelly - Sonata Seria; James - Four Poems of Michael Fried, Variations for Piano; Saylor - Loveplay; Gilbert - Gestures for Cello and Piano, March 9, 1977; ID: 390.0006 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0006)
    - Kronos Quartet, Benshoof - Refrains; Fennelly - String Quartet in two minutes; Mozart - Quartet #17 in Bflat, March 9, 1977; ID: 390.0007 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0007)
    - Handel - Sonata in F major; Kotonski - Monochromie; Fennelly - Scintilla Prisea; Schulman - Lieder, May 16, 1979; ID: 390.0008 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0008)
    - Levy - Five Progressions for 3 Mvts.; Kraft - Five pieces for Clarinet and Piano; Kotonsku - Monochromie, May 16 and November 20, 1979; ID: 390.0009 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0009)
    - Kraft - Five pieces for Clarinet and Piano; Karchin - Attuned to the Times; Saylor - Four Psalm Settings; Ghezzo - For Cello and Piano; Fennelly - Tesserae VII; Weugl - Songs Newly Seen in the Dusk; Levi - Five Progressions, November 25, 1979; ID: 390.0010 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0010)
    - Dinos Constantinides recital, December 10, 1979; ID: 390.0011 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0011)
    - Dinos Constantinides recital, December 10, 1979; ID: 390.0012 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0012)
    - Haydn; Fennelly; Schubert; Fennelly, March 25, 1980; ID: 390.0013 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0013)
    - Brahms - Piano Qt in G minor, March 25, 1980; ID: 390.0014 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0014)
    - Karchin - Trio for Flute, Cello, and Piano; Fennelly - Empirical Rag, April 17, 1980; ID: 390.0015 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0015)
    - WSCMS concert, October 20, 1980; ID: 390.0016 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0016)
    - Chasalow - Falling Forward; Schwartz - Just a Coupla Breaths; Davidovsky - Synchronisms no. 1; Saylor - St. Ulmo's Fire; Taxin Love Lyrucs; Schouthal - By the Roadside, February 3, 1981; ID: 390.0017 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0017)
    - Helen Vanni and the Arioso Trio - Copland - Vitebsk; Shoenberg - The Book of the Hanging Gardens; Cory - Designs; Biscardi - Trio; Fennelly - Empirical Rag, March 1, 1981; ID: 390.0018 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0018)
    - Child - Duo; Ghezzo - Three pieces for Solo Violin; Karchin - Chamber Concerto for Bassoon and Six Instruments, May 11, 1981; ID: 390.0019 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0019)
    - Kucera - Genesis; Shattenkirk - Interpolations; Fennelly - Sonata Seria; Babbitt - Minute Waltz, May 11, 1981; ID: 390.0020 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0020)
    - Riley - Canzona; Fennelly - Tesserae IVa; Yellin - Sonata for Cello and Piano; Macregor - Fitful Sleep; Gonzales - Voces I; Potter - Tuba Sonata, November 19, 1981; ID: 390.0021 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0021)
    - Wolpe and His Influence, March 4, 1982; ID: 390.0022 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0022)
    - Musica Nova, May 12, 1982; ID: 390.0023 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0023)
    - Musica Nova, May 12, 1982; ID: 390.0024 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0024)
    - Karchin - Viola Variations; Tower - Hexachords; Berio - Sequenza IV; Couper - Two Piano Rags; Lieverman - Metalwork; Fennelly - Tesserae IX; Babbitt - Partitions, Post Partitions, Reflections, Mat 20, 1982; ID: 390.0025 (Box 3, Media ID: 390.0025)
    - Pone - Woodland Elegies; Rochberg - Sonata Fantasia; Chenoweth - Songs, Sounds, Images; Fennelly - Suite for Doublebass; Yttrehus - Angstwagen, October 7, 1982; ID: 390.0026 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0026)
    - Rosenzweig - Four Songs; Fennelly - Tesserae II; Dembski - Alta; Martino - Fantasy Variations; Brickle - Memoir; Karchin - Duo; Olan - Three Poems; Ives - Six Songs, December 17. 1982; ID: 390.0027 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0027)
    - Occasional Singers / Peg Ahrens - Rhodes, Kernis, Powell, Berg, Levi, Caltabiano, Phillips, Fontyn, Ives, March 14, 1983; ID: 390.0028 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0028)
    - Stock - Icicle; Bielawa - Warp; Cage - Music for Wind Instruments; Zur - Four for Four; Karchin - Soliloquy; Carter - Night Fantasies, May 6, 1983; ID: 390.0029 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0029)
    - Retzhl - Poem; Shifrin - Trio (Arioso Trio), October 25, 1983; ID: 390.0030 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0030)
    - Wolpe - Form, Form IV; Stevermann - Trio (Arioso Trio), October 25, 1983; ID: 390.0031 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0031)
    - Wolpe - Form, Form IV; Stevermann - Trio, October 25, 1983; ID: 390.0032 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0032)
    - Rodriguez - Four Poems; Fennelly - Tesserae VII; Levi - This Much I Know; Messiaen 0 Trois Melodies; Anderson - Measure of Terrain; Kupferman - Song without Words; Bartok - Five Songs, Op. 15, December 16, 1983; ID: 390.0033 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0033)
    - Babbitt - Phonemena; Whittenberg - Three Pieces for Clarinet; Thorne - Lyric Variations No. 6; Festinger - Triptych; Brickle - Music for Violin and Piano, February 28, 1984; ID: 390.0034 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0034)
    - Schoenberg - Pierrot Lunaire, February 28, 1984; ID: 390.0035 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0035)
    - Karchin - Three Miniatures for Piano; Wuorinen - Violin Variations; Mumford - Barbaglio dal Manca, March 29, 1984; ID: 390.0036 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0036)
    - Kraft - Five Short Pieces and a Reprise; Brief - Moments; Cort - Ehre; Miller - Trio, March 29, 1984; ID: 390.0037 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0037)
    - Steven Gerber Duo in Three Movements; Fennelly - Canzona and Dance, November 5, 1984; ID: 390.0038 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0038)
    - Pone - Cyprian Sketches; Adler - Aeolus, God of the Winds, November 5, 1984; ID: 390.0039 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0039)
    - Carter - Canonic Suite; Jazwinshi - The Seventh Night of the Seventh Moon; Beglarian - Carinet Quartet; Bond - Peter Quince at the Clavier; Mozart - Adagio K 580 A; Schoenberg - Cabaret Songs, February 4, 1985; ID: 390.0040 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0040)
    - Bond - Peter Quince at the Clavier; Mozart - Adagio K580 A; Schoenberg - Cabaret Songs, Galathea, Einfaltiges Lied, Jedem das Seine, Arie aus dem Spiegal von Arkadien, February 4, 1985; ID: 390.0041 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0041)
    - Biggs - Years; Davies - Hymnos; Rosenzweig - Another Order of Cat; Kraft - Soliloquy; Eswards - Suspension Bridge; Karchin - Songs of John Keats, March 25, 1985; ID: 390.0042 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0042)
    - Ussachevsky - Pentagram; Schwartz - Second Thoughts; Barber - Hermet Songs; Reynolds - Summer Island, Octover 21, 1985; ID: 390.0043 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0043)
    - Babbitt - Vision and Prayer; Kraft - Diaphonics; Biggs - Northeast Reservations Lines, October 12, 1985; ID: 390.0044 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0044)
    - Moravec - Spirit Dance; Wagemans - Muziek Voor Basklarinet en Piano; Rzewski - Winnsboro Cotton Mill Blues; Primosch - Icons; Ives - Three-Page Sonata; Ewazen - Fantasy for Violin and Piano, December 17, 1985; ID: 390.0045 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0045)
    - American Brass Quintet - Elizabethan Consort Music; Thomas - Consonanze Stravaganti; Carter - Brass Quintet; Brahms / Fennelly - Three Chorale Preludes; Shapey - Brass Quintet; Fennelly - Empirical Rag; Dahl - Music for Brass Instruments, March 31, 1986; ID: 390.0048 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0048)
    - Debussy - Prelude a L'apres midi d'un Faune; Ravel - Oiseau Tristes, Allborado del Gracioso; Debussy - Elegie, Epigraphes Antiques, En Blanc et Noir; Bestor - The Second Moon of Venus, May 5, 1986; ID: 390.0046 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0046)
    - Karchin - Caprice; Fennelly - Tangoblique; Prokofiev - Sonata No. 8, May 5, 1986; ID: 390.0047 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0047)
    - Kurtag; Babbitt; Kurtag, March 1, 1987; ID: 390.0049 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0049)
    - Helps - Fantasy from "Serenade"; Feldman - Piece (1950); Stockhausen - In Freundschapt; Edwards - Trio for Violin, Horn, and Piano, January 10, 1988; ID: 390.0050 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0050)
    - Babbitt - The Joy of More Sextets; Helps - Postlude from "Serenade", January 10, 1988; ID: 390.0051 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0051)
    - Arnold Schonberg / Pierrot Lunaire, Undated; ID: 390.0052 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0052)
    - Cultural Council Foundation (for Washington Square), Undated; ID: 390.0053 (Box 4, Media ID: 390.0053)
    - Adams - China Gates; Karchin - Sonata for Piano; Biggs - Ave Formosissima, January 17, 1989; ID: 390.0054 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0054)
      Format: 1/4" Audiocassette
    - Roens - ...and Starry Skies; Goehr - Sonata for Cello and Piano, Op. 45; Weir - A Serbian Cabaret, February 23, 1989; ID: 390.0055 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0055)
    - Olan - Alborada; Peterson - Labyrinth; Chasalow - Over the Edge; Wuorinen - Horn Trio, March 21, 1990; ID: 390.0056 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0056)
    - MTC, Solerni, Peterson, March 23, 1993; ID: 390.0057 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0057)
    - Clayton, Boykan, Karchin, Perle, March 23, 1993; ID: 390.0058 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0058)
    - Karlins - Quartet for Strings; Biggs - A Consuming Fire; Karchin - Second String Quartet; Bauer - Aplomb; Mamlock - Polarities; Inbrie - Strings Quartet #4, List Momenent of Imbrie, November 30, 1995; ID: 390.0059 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0059)
    - Carter - Figment; Wieman - Villancico; Karchin - Sonata da Camera; Wuormen - Toshi, November 25, 1996; ID: 390.0060 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0060)
    - Knussen - Whitman Settings; Boykan - Sonata for Solo Violin; McMullin - Li Bai Songs; Leon - Bailarin; Karchin - Sarabano / Variation; Resenzweig - On the Wings of Wind, November 9, 1999; ID: 390.0061 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0061)
    - Murail - [Treiad] Couleurs; Nichols - Fantasy; Schumer - Sonata for Alto Sax and Piano; Durand - [Pacle feu recveilli]; Birtwistle - An Interrupted Endless Melody; Hoffman - Stone's Throw, December 7, 1999; ID: 390.0062 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0062)
    - Dakkaouccika, Webern, Martino, Wilson, Carter, Winn, Busoni, November 20, 2000; ID: 390.0063 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0063)
    - Dillon - Sgothan; Gordon - Tribeca; Karpen - Il Nome; Hoffman - I Stepped into the Dawn; Messiaen - Cauteyodjaya; Babbitt - Phenemena; Dillon - Redemption, December 11, 2001; ID: 390.0064 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0064)
    - Merkin Hall, 2001; ID: 390.0065 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0065)
    - Lennon, Jaffe, Chasalow, Dekki Joio (Master), Undated; ID: 390.0066 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0066)
    - Lennon, Jaffe, Chasalow, Dekki Joio, Undated; ID: 390.0067 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0067)
    - WSCMS / Colum, Sides A and B, Undated; ID: 390.0068 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0068)
    - WSCMS / Colum, Side C, Undated; ID: 390.0069 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0069)
    - WSCMS / Colum, Sides A and B, Undated; ID: 390.0070 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0070)
    - WSCMS / Colum, Side C, Undated; ID: 390.0071 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0071)
    - Merkin Hall concert, May 9, 1991; ID: 390.0072 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0072)
      Format: DAT
    - Lon Karchin - rehearsal, May 8, 1991; ID: 390.0073 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0073)
    - Merkin Hall concert - #1-1, March 23, 1993; ID: 390.0074 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0074)
    - Merkin Hall concert, November 29, 1994; ID: 390.0075 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0075)
    - Karchin - Second String Quartet, November 30, 1995; ID: 390.0076 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0076)
    - Merkin Hall concert, November 30, 1995; ID: 390.0077 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0077)
    - Merkin Hall concery (backup copy), November 30, 1995; ID: 390.0078 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0078)
    - Consortium #3, April 9, 1996; ID: 390.0079 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0079)
    - Wuorinen - Horn trio; Yim - Furiosamente; Rakowski - A Loose Gathering of Words; Moe - Time Will Tell; Kim - Three Poems in French; Peterson - Diptych, April 9, 1996; ID: 390.0080 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0080)
    - Carter - Figment; Wieman - Villancico; Karchin - Sonata du [Camdas]; Composers discussion, November 25, 1996; ID: 390.0081 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0081)
    - Merkin Hall concert, April 1, 1998; ID: 390.0082 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0082)
    - WCCMS Master, March [22], 1999; ID: 390.0083 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0083)
    - Knussen - Whitman Settings; Boykan - Sonata for Solo Violin; McMullin - Li Bai Songs, November 9, 1999; ID: 390.0084 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0084)
    - Murail - Three [Overtures]; Michols - Fantasy; Schuller - Sonata, December 7, 1999; ID: 390.0085 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0085)
    - WSCMS backup, March 23, 2000; ID: 390.0086 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0086)
    - Rolf Shulte, Violin; James Winn, Piano, November 20, 2000; ID: 390.0087 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0087)
    - WSCMS concert, December 12, 2000; ID: 390.0088 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0088)
    - Perle - Monody; Schwendinger - Rapture; Smaldone - Rituals, Sacret and Profane; Karchin - Galactic Folds, mvt I, II; Thomson - Three Portraits; Fennelly - Nocturne, Variations, Tocatta, October 15, 2001; ID: 390.0089 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0089)
    - Merkin Hall concert, December 11, 2001; ID: 390.0090 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0090)
    - WSCMS concert, 2001; ID: 390.0091 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0091)
    - WSCMS concert, March 19, 2002; ID: 390.0092 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0092)
    - Merkin Hall concert, March 26, 2003; ID: 390.0093 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0093)
    - Washington Square Contemporary Music Ensemble at Merkin Hall, October 13, 2003; ID: 390.0094 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0094)
    - Merkin Hall concert, December 9, 2003; ID: 390.0095 (Box 5, Media ID: 390.0095)